I've been here before...
我曾經一次又一次地
over and over again, and each time the same question.
經歷這樣的場景 每次會問自己相同的問題
Is this it?
就這一次嗎
Will this time be the one?
這會是命定最后的一次嗎
And each time the same answer.
每次的答案都一樣
And I'm just so tired of it.
我真的已經厭倦了
永生守衛
■
摩洛哥
You good?
你好嗎
You travel?
去旅行了
I did.
沒錯
And I got you something.
我給你帶了東西
What's that?
是什么
Ooh, first edition Don Quixote.
初版的《堂吉訶德》
That couldn't have been cheap. It wasn't.
肯定不便宜吧 的確
So why am I here, Booker?
為什么叫我來這里 布克
You remember Surabaya eight years ago, right?
你還記得八年前在蘇臘巴亞發生的事吧
CIA.
中情局
Yeah. The guy who hired us, James Copley, reached out.
沒錯 當時雇我們的詹姆斯·科普利聯系我
He's freelance now.
他現在自己單干
He has a hostage situation in South Sudan.
他手上有個南蘇丹解救人質的活
No, Booker. We don't do repeats. You know that.
不行 布克 同一個人不接觸二次 你懂規矩
It's too risky.
風險太大
Andy.
安迪
Joe and Nicky?
喬和尼基在嗎
At the hotel.
在酒店
Come back again.
歡迎下次再來
Thank you very much. Welcome to El Fenn, sir.
謝謝 歡迎來到厄爾芬恩酒店 先生
Checking in? Oui.
入住登記嗎 是的
What brings you to Marrakesh? Family.
來馬拉喀什做什么 探親
敘利亞爆發危機  20名兒童被殺  100多名受傷
突發新聞
海地政局動蕩  抗議活動第二天1死35傷
Say, "Marrakesh!"
說 "馬拉喀什"
Marrakesh!
馬拉喀什
Would you like me to take one for you?
用不用我幫你們拍一張
Oh, thank you so much. I just really suck at taking selfies.
非常感謝 我很不會拍自拍
There you go. Thank you!
好了 謝謝
You look great. You look okay.
你看上去很棒 你看上去還行
Thank you! Thank you!
謝謝 謝謝
And I have something for you.
我有東西要給你
Nicky!
尼基
Baklava.
果仁蜜餅
Five hundred, Booker.
賭五百塊 布克
No.
不是吧
All right.
好吧
All in. Here it is. Really?
全投 拿著 真的嗎
All in! All in!
全投 全投
Hazelnut, not walnut.
是榛子 不是核桃
The Black Sea.
黑海
Rosewater.
玫瑰水
Pomegranate.
石榴
Eastern Turkey.
土耳其東部
No, no, no. Don't worry.
不不不 別擔心
Admit it, boss. You missed us.
承認吧 老大 你想我們了
I did.
是的
It's a job, guys.
有份差事 伙計們
We can do some good.
我們能做些好事
Have you been watching the news lately?
你最近看新聞了嗎
Some good means nothing.
做好事沒什么意義
I don't know about this, guys.
我們真的要做嗎 伙計們
We're not helping.
我們幫不上忙
I know you needed a break, but it's been over a year, boss.
我知道你想休息 老大 但已經過去一年了
This is what we do, Andy.
我們就是做這個的 安迪
I'll hear him out.
我聽聽他怎么說吧
Mr. Copley.
科普利先生
Mr. Booker, bonjour.
布克先生 你好
It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
終于見到你了 真是榮幸
Last time I checked, you had to be American to be in the CIA.
我記得只有美國人才能加入中情局吧
I was born in Boston.
我出生在波士頓
Moved to London when I was three.
三歲的時候搬到了倫敦
So why did you leave the agency, Mr. Copley?
那你為什么離開中情局呢 科普利先生
My wife got sick.
我妻子生病了
AlS.
肌萎縮側索硬化
She died two years ago.
她兩年前去世了
Just haven't found my way back yet.
我還沒緩過勁來
Sorry for your loss. Thank you.
請節哀 謝謝
You haven't aged a day, Booker.
你一點也沒變老 布克
Trust me, I have.
相信我 老了許多
Yesterday afternoon local,
當地昨天下午發生一起事故
a school southwest of Juba was attacked by a militia.
朱巴西南區一所學校遭到民兵組織襲擊
They murdered the teachers
民兵組織殺害了教師
and abducted 17 of the students at gunpoint.
持槍綁架了十七名學生
紐約時報
聯合國譴責南蘇丹發生的兒童綁架事件
The youngest was eight...
最小的孩子只有八歲
oldest, 13.
最大的十三歲
South Sudanese asked the US for help,
南蘇丹向美國尋求援助
but current administration's policy
但現政府的政策
is to deny aid to any nonstrategic allies.
是拒絕援助任何非戰略性盟友
Some of my ex colleagues at the CIA feel differently.
但我在中情局有些前同事不認可這種政策
They reached out to me, and I'm reaching out to you.
他們找到了我 然后我又找到了你
The last overfly confirmed the personnel on site.
最后一次空中偵察確認被綁架孩子都在學校
No food or water being brought in.
沒有人帶食物和水進去
That means they're moving them soon.
說明他們很快要將孩子轉移走
And when they do,
一旦被轉移
most likely they'll be separated,
孩子們極有可能被分散
and odds are we'll never find them again.
我們再想找到他們就難了
Has to be done quickly...
一定要精銳部隊
by the best, and your team's the best I've ever seen.
快速拿下 你的團隊是我見過最棒的
You can name your price.
你可以隨便開價
We'll invoice you when it's done.
等任務結束我們會給你賬單
■
南蘇丹
Peace be with you.
愿你們平安
What the...
什么...
Are we too late?
我們來晚了嗎
Motherfuck...
媽的...
Room clear!
屋內安全
Oh, my God! Shit!
天啊 該死
Look out! Reload!
小心 重新填彈
What the hell?
什么情況
What's wrong?
怎么回事
What the fuck...
什么鬼
Everyone still with me? Yeah.
大家都沒事吧 嗯
Joe?
喬
Very pissed off.
氣炸了
So where are the girls?
女孩們在哪里
There never were any girls.
根本沒什么女孩
We've been set up.
我們被設計了
Yeah, I got it.
弄到了
尼基  喬 安迪  布克? 1864年6月
One has to admire Mr. Copley's attention to detail.
科普利先生對細節的把控令人佩服
Those shoes were a particularly grotesque touch.
那些鞋選得尤其巧妙
I knew this was gonna happen.
我就知道會發生這種事
I said it.
我說過的
We did it right, Andy.
我們沒做錯 安迪
For the right reasons.
是為了正義的理由
And what did it get us, Nicky? What?
但是正義給我們帶來了什么 尼基 什么
Nothing.
什么也沒有
We've done nothing.
我們什么都沒做成
The world isn't getting any better.
世界不會因為我們的努力變好
It's getting worse.
反而在變糟
I checked him completely, and...
我仔細地查過他的背景 結果...
everything seemed legit.
看上去都沒什么問題
I'm sorry, guys.
抱歉 伙計們
They know who we are. They know what we are.
他們知道我們的底細 知道我們的能力
We have to find Copley.
我們得找到科普利
We have to tie this thing off.
我們必須了結此事
And then what? And then nothing.
然后呢 然后什么也不做
The world can burn for all I care.
哪怕世界毀滅我也不在乎
I'm done.
我不干了
■
阿富汗
Freeman, where you at?
弗里曼 你在哪
Here, Sergeant.
這里 中士
The women are holed up in the house with the arches.
婦女們被關在有拱門的房子里
Take a right at the building with the red carpet.
在有紅地毯的房子處右轉
Get me some information. Roger that.
給我探聽一下情況 收到
Keep it respectful.
不要動粗
Don't we always?
我們不是一直如此嗎
Never hurts to repeat it.
多說幾遍也沒什么不好
My name is Nile.
我叫奈爾
I am an American Marine.
我是美國海軍陸戰隊的
We are looking for this man.
我們在找這個人
He has killed many of our people and many of yours.
他殺了很多我們和你們的人
Have any of you seen him?
你們見過他嗎
You do not disrespect your family
告訴我們他的行蹤
by telling us where he is.
并不算對家族的不敬
There are no men here.
這里沒有男人
To use women as shields is to be no man at all.
拿女人做擋箭牌可算不得男人
Thank you for allowing us into your home.
謝謝你允許我們進入你家
We will leave you in peace.
我們就不打擾你們了
Breach!
破門
Stop!
住手
Clear! Covering! Clear!
安全 掩護 安全
Lima 3, this is India 5. Contact, over.
L3 我是I5 遇敵 完畢
Jay, go check on the women.
杰 去看看女人們怎么樣了
On it.
馬上
Look at all this shit. It's jackpot.
看看這些東西 中頭彩了
Not if he bleeds out. They wanted him alive, remember?
他失血過多死了就壞了 他們要活捉 記得嗎
Do not...
別...
Do not touch me.
別碰我
I'm trying to save you, man.
我是在救你
Dizzy, a little help, please?
迪齊 幫幫忙好嗎
No! Medic!
不 醫療兵
Man down!
有人受傷
No! Jesus! Medic!
不 天啊 醫療兵
Stay with me!
堅持住
Oh, my...
天啊
God! Jesus, no.
天啊 不
Come here. Stay with me. Look at me.
拜托 堅持住 看著我
Look at me. You're gonna be okay.
看著我 你會沒事的
Nile! Nile!
奈爾 奈爾
You're okay. It's okay.
你沒事的 會好的
Stay with me. Just look at me. Look at me.
堅持住 看著我 看著我
Okay. Medic's on their way. Medic's on their way.
好了 醫療兵要來了 馬上到
No, no. It's okay. It's okay.
不 不 沒事的 沒事的
The medic's coming!
醫療兵來了
What the...
什么...
No.
不
No, not another one.
不 別再來一個
Not now.
現在不行
It was a woman.
是一個女人
A black woman.
黑人女子
I saw an older woman in a hijab.
我看到一個戴頭巾的年長女性
What did you see?
你看到了什么
I saw...
我看到...
I saw part of a name tag.
我看到胸牌的一角
Free... free something.
弗里...弗里什么
Yeah. Dirt floor, clay walls.
對 泥地 土墻
And a medevac.
還有空中救護
Yeah, so maybe a, uh... a coalition...
對 所以可能是什么...聯軍
medical team.
醫療隊
The knife was a pesh kabz. Pashtun.
是一把佩什喀短刀 普什圖人用的
I felt her die.
我感受到了她的死亡
She's a Marine.
她是海軍陸戰隊的
Combat.
作戰人員
Or near combat duty.
或是作戰相關人員
Afghanistan.
阿富汗
It's been over 200 years.
已經兩百多年了
Why now?
為什么現在出現
Everything happens for a reason, boss.
萬事皆有因 老大
We have to find her.
我們得找到她
No, we stick to the plan. We find Copley.
不 我們按計劃行動 找到科普利
So we just leave her out in the open? No, we're in the open.
我們就任她暴露嗎 不 暴露的是我們
We're the ones who are exposed now. Not like her.
現在暴露的是我們 但和她情況不同
Nicky...
尼基...
Not like her.
和她情況不同
You can't tell me you don't remember what it was like.
別告訴我你不記得那種感受了
Whoever she is, she's confused, and she's scared,
不管她是誰 她都感到困惑 害怕
and she's more alone than she has ever been in her entire life.
她正處于這輩子最孤獨的時刻
We all remember what it was like.
我們都記得那種感受
She needs us.
她需要我們
I'll handle the retrieval.
我去把她帶回來
Hey, boss, come on.
老大 別這樣
If we're dreaming about her, she's dreaming about us.
如果我們夢到了她 她也夢到了我們
That makes her a beacon straight to us.
她成了暴露我們蹤跡的燈塔
What do we do in the meantime? Get to France.
那我們做什么呢 去法國
Use the Charlie safe house.
去安全屋C
I'll meet you there.
我們在那里匯合
Find Copley.
找到科普利
Jesus.
老天
She's just a baby.
她還是個孩子
I know I saw her die.
我看到她死了
A little blood can look like a lot.
流的血可能沒有看上去那么多
Adrenaline flying, everyone was seeing shit they didn't.
腎上腺素飆升 大家都可能看錯
I was holding her neck together in my hands.
我當時雙手按著她的脖子
You'd rather we sent her home in a body bag?
你寧愿我們把她裹在尸袋里送回家嗎
No, of course not.
不 當然不是
So come on.
那就別想了
Hey, look who's up.
看看誰起來了
Nile?
奈爾
What's up, Jay?
你好啊 杰
What's up, Dizzy?
你好啊 迪齊
So let's see the trophy.
讓我們看看傷疤吧
Fuck me.
我操
Nile, there's not even a scratch.
奈爾 一點印子都沒留下
Yeah, they, uh...
是 他們...
They used this new skin graft or something.
他們用了最新的植皮技術什么的
That what the doctor said?
醫生是這么說的嗎
Yeah.
對
That's what they said.
他們就是這么說的
梅里克
Our average lifespan is 78 in developed nations.
發達國家的平均壽命是78歲
■
倫敦
英國
Actually, two more years
實際上 如果你有幸是女性
if you're lucky enough to be born a female.
還能多活兩歲
What can I say, ladies?
真是羨慕 女士們
Now, all of this
所有這一切
is because of everyone's favorite love to hate...
都是因為大家又愛又恨的...
Big Pharma.
大型制藥公司
At my company, our research on telomere extension
在我的公司 我們對于端粒延展的研究
has reversed the chromosomal clock of human stem cells.
已經逆轉了人類干細胞的染色體時鐘
Dr. Kozak's manipulation of the klotho hormone will, in time,
科扎克博士對于可羅索激素的使用將在未來
completely arrest common cognitive decline.
完全阻止常見的認知退化
Yes, we can all wave goodbye to dementia.
沒錯 我們都可以和癡呆說再見了
Now... wait!
等等
Our work will add years of life
我們的工作將會
to the collective world population.
使全世界人口的壽命增加幾年
Years. Decades.
幾年 幾十年
But it's not cheap.
但這并不便宜
We need investment.
我們需要投資
Investment drives my enthusiasm to take risks.
投資驅使我去冒險
These risks improve countless lives.
這些風險則會讓無數生命得到提升
My God.
我的天
You've seen my research.
你看過我的研究
Now you know they're for real.
現在你知道他們是真的了
What about the hard proof?
有確鑿的證據嗎
Blood, tissue, bone, DNA.
血液 組織 骨頭 DNA
Recovering an uncontaminated sample
從現場采集未受污染的樣本
of the site proved impossible.
是不可能的
But you promised me hard proof.
但你說了會有確鑿的證據
There was an unanticipated amount of carnage.
當時發生了意想不到的大規模殺戮
But the footage... No, no.
但視頻... 不 不
The footage is a two million dollar snuff film.
這個視頻是一部成本兩百萬美元的虐殺電影
It doesn't give her the how.
無法讓她知道是如何辦到的
I need all of them, Copley.
我要他們所有人 科普利
I think I can get you one. No. No, not one. All.
我應該能給你一個 不 一個不行 要所有人
These are extraordinary individuals.
這些人都體質非凡
They are extremely resistant to capture.
想抓他們萬分困難
Well, consult with Keane, make a plan, make it happen.
那和基恩商量一下 制定計劃 去實施
And quickly, before my competitors get wind of this.
動作要快 別讓我的競爭對手聽到風聲
梅里克
Corporal Freeman.
弗里曼下士
Aye, Sergeant. Orders just came through.
是 中士 剛才接到命令
They're sending you to Landstuhl, Germany for more tests.
他們派你去德國蘭茨圖爾做更多檢查
But I'm fine.
但我沒事
Plane's fueling. Pack your bags.
飛機正在加油 去收拾行李
Sergeant... We took these off you when it happened.
中士... 當時我們從你身上取下了這個
Didn't think you were coming back.
沒想到你能活下來
That's her.
就是她
Corporal Freeman.
弗里曼下士
Been looking for you.
一直在找你
Wheels up on your ride.
你的飛機要起飛了
Who are you? Andromache the Scythian.
你是誰 塞西亞人安德洛瑪刻
But you can call me Andy.
不過你可以叫我安迪
Why does it have to be so goddamn slow the first couple of times?
為什么最開始的幾次總是這么慢
You shot me.
你開槍打我
I did. I need you to get back in the car, please.
是的 請你回車上去
This isn't real. No, none of this is real.
這不是真的 不 這都不是真的
You haven't figured this out yet? You can't die.
你還沒弄清楚嗎 你死不了的
Get up.
起來吧
Fuck!
操
Can you please not do that again?
能請你別這么做了嗎
Who are you?
你是誰
I lead a group of immortals.
我領導一群永生者
An army, I guess.
算是一支隊伍吧
Soldiers. Fighters like you.
士兵 像你這樣的斗士
Look...
聽著...
You've got questions, kid.
你有疑問 小鬼
I get it.
我明白
You want answers?
你想知道答案嗎
Get back in the car.
回車上去
Put those on.
換上這個
Where are you taking me? Paris.
你要帶我去哪 巴黎
You've got blood in your hair. Wonder why?
你頭發上有血 是拜誰所賜呢
This guy's a drug runner.
這人是毒販子
This the shit you into?
你是做這行的
Well, sometimes you gotta work with people
有時候不得不和
you don't wanna eat with.
你不喜歡的人合作
Is this even safe?
這安全嗎
Does it really matter?
有關系嗎
Hey, boss.
老大
You found Copley?
找到科普利了嗎
Nothing but dead ends.
全是死胡同
He knows we're hunting him.
他知道我們在追蹤他
Keep looking.
繼續找
He's doing the same to us.
他也在追蹤我們
I have the new one.
我找到新人了
And?
然后呢
Well, she stabbed me, so I think she has potential.
她捅了我一刀 算她有潛力吧
I'll see you soon.
回頭見
So why is this happening to me?
我為什么會變成這樣
I wish I knew.
我也希望我知道
You said you had answers.
你說了你有答案
I didn't say you'd like them.
但我沒說你會喜歡我的答案
Are you praying?
你在祈禱嗎
God doesn't exist.
上帝并不存在
My God does.
我的上帝存在
You know, there was a time when I was worshiped as a god.
曾經我也被當做神一樣崇拜
Was that Him?
是上帝嗎
Don't worry, I can't do shit like that.
別擔心 我沒有這種能力
None of it means anything anyway.
反正那些都沒有意義了
You said there were others.
你說了還有其他人
How many?
有多少
Four.
四個
You're an army of four?
你的隊伍有四個人
So that's why you took me?
所以你帶上了我
So I could join your army?
好讓我加入你的隊伍
Yeah.
是的
No. This is some bullshit.
不 太扯了
You must...
你一定是...
Must have hypnotized me, or...
一定是催眠了我 或是...
or, uh, drugged me or something.
或是給我下了藥什么的
And that was a blank that you shot me with.
你給我的那一槍是空包彈吧
And I was the one who cut your throat.
那割你喉嚨的人也是我了
Right?
對嗎
Listen, kid.
聽著 小鬼
You already believe in...
反正你都相信上帝了
You should just keep following that illogic.
你應該繼續相信不合邏輯的事
You're already on board with the supernatural.
你早就相信超自然力量了
If I were you, I'd get some sleep.
你最好睡一會
We're not going to Paris.
我們不去巴黎了
Andrei.
安德烈
Come here.
過來
Sit your ass down!
給我坐下
Stand up! You do not listen to her.
站起來 別聽她的
You listen to me.
你要聽我的
Land this plane.
立刻降落
Trust me. She's not gonna shoot you.
相信我 她不會向你開槍的
I am.
但我會
Who's gonna fly the plane?
誰來駕駛飛機
We don't need a pilot.
我們不需要飛行員
We can jump and survive.
我們跳下去也不會死
I am not jumping from a plane!
我才不要跳飛機
Shit! Maybe we do need a pilot.
該死 或許我們真的需要飛行員
I can fly a plane.
我會開飛機
You don't speak Russian, do you?
你不會說俄語吧
Why?
怎么了
Because I told the pilot to play dead.
因為我剛才讓飛行員裝死
You really want to do this, kid?
你真想這么做嗎 小鬼
We're done.
到此為止
I said we're done.
我說了到此為止
You're very good.
你身手很不錯
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Nile.
奈爾
You see? You're already healing faster.
看吧 愈合速度已經變快了
Is this real?
這是真的嗎
I got people that love me.
我有愛我的人
People that are gonna worry.
會為我擔心的人
I'm a Marine.
我是海軍陸戰隊員
They think I went AWOL. You're not a Marine anymore.
他們會認為我是逃兵 你不再是海軍陸戰隊員了
They're going to lock you up.
他們會把你關起來
■
古桑維爾
法國
I thought you said we were going to Paris.
你不是說我們要去巴黎嗎
We're just outside of Paris.
我們就在巴黎城外
This is Goussainville.
這里是古桑維爾
This place has been abandoned for 50 years.
這里已經廢棄五十年了
Why?
為什么
So are you good guys or bad guys?
你們是好人還是壞人
Depends on the century.
取決于是哪個世紀
We fight for what we think is right.
我們為自己眼中的正義而戰
How are you all in my dreams?
你們為什么都出現在了我的夢里
We dream of each other. They stop when we meet.
我們會夢到對方 直到我們相遇
Why?
為什么
I believe it's because we... we're meant to find each other.
我認為是因為我們注定要找到彼此
It's like destiny.
像命中注定一樣
No, more like misery loves company.
不 更像是同病相憐
What he said.
他說得沒錯
It used to take years to track a new one.
以前要花上幾年才能找到一個新伙伴
Booker was the last.
布克是最后一位
1812.
1812年
No way.
不可能
Yeah, I died fighting with Napoleon.
真的 我死在跟拿破侖的戰斗中
So... you're even older than him.
所以你比他年紀還大
Nicky and I met in the Crusades.
我和尼基在十字軍東征時期認識的
The Crusades?
十字軍東征
The love of my life was of the people I've been taught to hate.
他是我此生摯愛 也是我本該憎恨的人
We...
我們
We killed each other.
我們殺死了對方
Many times.
很多次
You're the oldest.
你是年紀最大的
Yeah.
是的
So how old are you?
你到底有多老
Old. How old?
很老 多老
Too old.
太老了
So we really never die.
我們真的永生不死
Nothing that lives lives forever.
只要有生命 就不會永生
But... you said that we were immortal.
但...你說過我們是永生的
I know what I said.
我知道我說過
And we mostly are, but we can die.
我們幾乎是永生的 但也會死
And one of us did.
我們其中一人就死了
He...
他...
He was a warrior, just like us.
他曾是一名戰士 和我們一樣
A long time ago.
那是很久以前了
One day your wounds just don't heal up anymore, and...
有一天傷口就不再愈合了
we don't know when or why.
我們不知道會在何時 也不知道原因
So if we can die,
如果我們會死
then why would you shoot me?
你為什么要朝我開槍
You could have killed me.
你有可能殺死我
You're too new.
你還太嫩
It is a lot to understand.
你還有很多不理解的
I think you should get some rest.
我覺得你現在需要休息一下
Come with me.
跟我來
I'll show you.
我帶你去看看
She wants to talk to her family.
她想跟家人聯系
That's not gonna help her.
那對她沒什么好處
You tell her that.
你去跟她說
What's going on?
怎么了
What happened?
發生什么了
It's just a... a bad dream.
只是...做了個噩夢
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Tell us.
跟我們說說
I saw flashes of it before...
我之前也夢到過這些片段...
when I first dreamt of all of you.
那時我剛開始夢到你們
But now it's clearer.
但現在夢更清晰了
I dreamed about a woman locked in an iron coffin...
我夢到一個女人 被鎖在一個鐵棺材里
under the sea.
沉在海底
She kept...
她不斷地
drowning and then coming back to life.
淹死 又活過來
She was hammering her bloody fists and knees against the iron.
她不停地錘打鐵壁 直到拳頭和膝蓋滿是血痕
She felt like something insane, something furious.
感覺她是那么瘋狂和憤怒
But she kept fighting...
但她沒有停止反抗
and she kept drowning.
然后不斷地淹死
Her name was Quynh.
她叫瓊
She was one of us.
她曾是我們的同伴
The first immortal Andy found.
第一個被安迪發現的永生者
They had been alone so long, when she found her...
她們都獨自生活太久了 當安迪找到她時
Quynh had given up.
瓊已經放棄了
Way back, it was her and Andy.
很久之前 只有安迪和她
Before me and Nicky, it was just the two of them.
在尼基和我出現之前 只有她們二人
They ran through the world together.
她們一起走遍世界
Fought thousands of battles side by side.
并肩作戰 打過數不清的戰役
She was a pit viper in a fight.
她如同毒蛇般兇殘
They were in England,
當時她們在英格蘭
freeing so called heretics from the witch trials.
從獵巫審判中解救那些所謂的異教徒
But then, Andy and Quynh,
但當時安迪和瓊
they were accused of witchcraft themselves,
她們自己也被指控使用巫術
and they were trapped and caught. Killers!
并且被誘捕了 殺人犯
Some will rot in hell!
下地獄吧
When they didn't die, it proved their case,
她們沒有死 這證明了她們的罪行
and they got sentenced again and again.
她們一遍又一遍地被處以極刑
I've never been burned alive before.
我從未試過被活活燒死
What do you think it's gonna be like?
你覺得會是什么感覺
Excruciating.
肯定很痛苦
Just you and me.
只有你我
Until the end.
直到最后
No! No!
不 不
No, not this.
不 不要這樣
No! Where are you taking her?
不要 你們要帶她去哪
You are too powerful together.
你們兩人在一起太強大了
For creatures such as you, there is no salvation.
你們這樣的怪物 永遠得不到救贖
Please! No!
求你了 不要
Quynh!
瓊
Andromache!
安德洛瑪刻
No!
不要
After Andy escaped, we spent decades searching for her
安迪逃出來之后 我們花了數十年尋找她
or anyone on that ship who could tell us where she was cast off.
或者那艘船上能告訴我們具體地點的人
She's lived with that guilt ever since,
自那之后 她一直滿懷愧疚
but she blames herself for Quynh's fate.
她把瓊的遭遇歸咎于自己
Why do you blame yourself?
為什么你要怪罪自己
I lost a soldier.
我失去了一名戰士
I feel her pain.
我能感受到她的痛苦
Her rage.
她的憤怒
She feels crazy.
好像瘋了一樣
Over 500 years in a box at the bottom of the ocean...
在海底的鐵箱子里關了五百多年
would make anyone insane.
任誰都會瘋了
That's the reason why we dread capture.
正是因為如此 我們才如此害怕被捕
Spend eternity in a cage.
關在牢籠里的永生
Nile.
奈爾
I don't want this.
我不想要這能力
I don't want any of it.
一點都不想要
I know. I know.
我明白 我明白
There isn't one good thing in any of this.
這能力沒有任何好處
I know this is hard.
我知道這很難接受
It's happening whether you want it or not.
但這由不得你
I know you're scared, Nile.
奈爾 我明白你害怕了
Me and those three men in there will keep you safe.
我們會好好保護你的
Like Quynh?
像保護瓊一樣嗎
We're all you've got.
你只有我們
What's happening?
發生什么了
They found us.
他們找到我們了
Joe? Nicky?
喬 尼基
Shit.
靠
Booker.
布克
You still with me?
你還好嗎
Clear the back room. Find Joe and Nicky.
去檢查后面的房間 去找喬和尼基
Book.
布克
Come on.
快點
Come back to me.
醒過來
You're still in this shitty game with me.
這游戲我們還沒玩完呢
You hear me?
聽到了嗎
Now wake up.
快點醒過來
Wake up!
醒過來
They're not here.
他們不見了
Welcome back, asshole.
混蛋 歡迎活過來
Thanks for taking your time.
花這么久 真是辛苦你了
It hurts everywhere.
全身都疼
How bad is it?
有多嚴重
It's an improvement.
對你來說是改良
How many?
對方多少人
I don't know.
我不知道
Where are Nicky and Joe? I don't know!
喬和尼基呢 我不知道
I... I turned on the game.
我打開電視看球賽
A grenade hit me.
就被手榴彈擊中了
Lost the plot after that.
之后就失去意識了
Two in transport. No, no. We need the woman.
抓了兩個 不 我們要那個女的
Wasn't there, and the other guy's in pieces.
女的不在 另一個男的死透了
She's there.
她在那
Copley. Copley?
是科普利 科普利
They're coming back. They want all of us.
他們找上我們了 他們想一網打盡
You stay here.
你們留在這里
Wait for my signal.
等我信號
What signal?
什么信號
What does that even mean? You'll know it when it comes.
那到底什么意思 到時候你就知道了
And, by the way, it's not always like this now.
另外 我們不是總這樣的
Big wounds take longer to heal.
大傷口的愈合時間更長
Sure.
肯定的
Bravo Team approaching church.
B隊接近教堂
Go, go, go.
上 上 上
Come on! Move! Move!
上 快點 快點
We've gotta get out there!
我們得出去
We need to help her.
我們得去幫她
No, that's not the signal.
不 還沒等到信號
Mr. Keane,
基恩先生
I strongly recommend that we leave right now.
我強烈建議立刻撤退
Come on!
快點
Let's move!
該走了
Wait for the signal.
等信號
How the hell can you even tell?
你怎么知道什么是信號
Let's go!
走吧
Andy did all this herself?
這都是安迪一個人干的嗎
Yeah. That woman has forgotten more ways to kill
對 那女人忘掉的殺人手法
than entire armies will ever learn.
比軍隊能學會的還多
Who are they? How'd they find you?
他們是誰 怎么找到你們的
I don't know. Let's go!
不知道 走吧
Nicolo.
尼古拉
Quiet. Nicolo, wake up.
閉嘴 尼古拉 醒醒
I said... I know what you said.
我說... 我知道你說了什么
What are you gonna do? Kill me?
你能怎樣 殺了我嗎
Wake up.
醒醒
Wake up!
I'm here.
我醒了
Wherever here is.
這是哪里
In an armored van.
在一輛裝甲車上
They used gas.
他們用了毒氣
I told you, shut up!
我說了 閉嘴
I need to know he's okay.
我得確認他沒事
That's sweet.
真貼心
What is he? Your boyfriend?
他是你男朋友嗎
You're a child.
你還是個孩子
An infant.
嬰兒
Your mocking is thus infantile.
你的嘲笑十分幼稚
He's not my boyfriend.
他不是我的男朋友
This man is more to me than you can dream.
他對我的重要性是你無法想象的
He's the moon when I'm lost in darkness
當我迷失在黑夜 他就是那輪明月
and warmth when I shiver in cold.
當我在寒冷中瑟瑟發抖 他帶給我溫暖
And his kiss still thrills me, even after a millennia.
即使跨越一千年 他的吻仍讓我顫抖
His heart overflows with the kindness
他的心中滿懷善意
of which this world is not worthy of.
這個世界根本配不上他
I love this man beyond measure and reason. He's not my boyfriend.
我愛這個男人勝過一切 他才不是我的男朋友
He's all and he's more.
他是我的全部 甚至更多
You're an incurable romantic.
你的浪漫真是無藥可救
I don't suppose it would be possible
有可能給我們
to get these chains off of us?
松個綁嗎
Get 'em out, Get 'em out! Get 'em on the plane now!
快把他們弄出來 立刻送他們上飛機
I guess not.
看來沒可能
We are usually a better judge of character.
我們看人一般沒這么不準
I suppose you are taking us to the person
我想你要帶我們去見
who paid for your betrayal.
那個收買你的人吧
It's a nice plane.
這飛機不錯
There's a TV, Joe.
還有電視呢 喬
Champagne?
有香檳嗎
■
銀谷
法國
What is this place?
這是什么地方
An abandoned mine.
一處廢棄的礦井
We stumbled on it during the Baussenque Wars.
我們在伯桑克戰爭時期偶然發現的
1150s maybe?
好像是1150年代
I used to keep my stuff here.
我以前會把東西存在這里
Is this a Rodin?
這是羅丹的作品嗎
Yeah.
對
This is an honest to God Rodin.
這居然是貨真價實的羅丹
Wait.
等等
Did you know him?
你認識他嗎
Probably biblically.
可能還有過一腿
Get to work finding Copley.
著手去找科普利吧
He's got Nicky and Joe.
尼基和喬在他手上
梅里克
It can hardly be unique if they can make another copy.
如果他們能復制 它就不可能獨一無二
I've got to go.
我得掛了
Ah! Gentlemen, welcome.
先生們 歡迎光臨
I am truly honored to meet you.
能見到你們 我深感榮幸
Together, we shall do such things.
我們攜手 能成就不凡之事
What they are yet, I know not,
我尚不知道此事的真貌
but they shall be the terrors of the Earth.
但它們必是人間之災禍
Or, um, rather the saviors.
亦或人間之解藥
Lear...
《李爾王》
Shakespeare.
莎士比亞寫的
Can we take the cuffs off?
能把手銬取了嗎
No, sir. We can't.
不 先生 不能取
My apologies.
抱歉
Let's get off on the right foot, shall we?
我們重新開始 如何
I'm Steven Merrick, youngest CEO in pharma.
我是史蒂文·梅里克 制藥界最年輕的CEO
Our work here is all about balance.
我們的工作講究平衡
How do we push the scientific frontiers
在推進科學進步的同時
whilst also turning a little profit?
順便掙點小錢
There's your balance, asshole.
你要的平衡 混蛋
Mr. Merrick? Yes, yes, yes.
梅里克先生 我知道了 知道了
Watch it.
小心點
Mr. Copley provided me with footage of your unique talent,
科普利先生給我看了記錄你們獨特天賦的錄像
but I prefer my evidence to be indisputable.
可我更喜歡眼見為實
No!
不
Mr. Merrick!
梅里克先生
God damn it!
該死
Shit!
靠
What do you see?
你看到什么了
The Nobel Prize.
諾貝爾獎
And a fair few quid to boot.
還有能榨取的利益
We brought a cancer drug to the market last quarter.
上個季度 我們上市了一種抗癌藥物
It's already saved hundreds of thousands of lives.
它已經挽救了成千上萬人的性命
Yet, in development,
可在研發過程中
it killed a quarter of a million lab mice.
這種藥物殺死了幾十萬只實驗小鼠
Now, I didn't ask for their little permissions.
我可沒征求那些小鼠的同意
I'm not gonna ask for yours.
同樣也不會征求你們的同意
He thinks you're a mouse, Nicky.
他覺得你是老鼠 尼基
There's genetic code inside you
你們體內的遺傳密碼
which could help every human being on Earth.
能夠拯救地球上每一個人
We're morally obliged to take it.
取走它是我們的道德義務
What?
什么
What is that? Wait!
你要干嘛 等等
No!
不
I'll keep you informed of my progress.
我會隨時向你匯報進展
Yes. Yes, you do that.
好的 就這么辦
Mr. Merrick...
梅里克先生
this is about science,
此事的重點是科學
not profits...
不是利益
or sadism.
更不是施虐
You owe me two more.
你還欠我兩個人
Come on, Book. You've been working on that for hours.
快點啊 布克 你查了好幾個小時了
He's a security expert.
他是個安全專家
He leaves no footprints. It's gonna take time.
沒留下任何蹤跡 得費點時間了
You got a satellite link?
你連衛星鏈路了嗎
Yeah.
連了
Follow the money.
追蹤錢的去向
Whoever he's working for, maybe?
或許能找到雇他的人
That's how we track militants.
我們就是這么追查激進分子的
I'm sure you already tried that.
不過你肯定已經試過了
Yeah, it won't hurt to try again.
再試一次無傷大雅
You know how it works, Nile.
你知道這事會如何發展 奈爾
Get some sleep while you can.
趁著有時間趕緊睡一會吧
I brought you a change of clothes.
我給你帶了干凈衣服
I'm going out for a bit.
我要出去一趟
Are you all right, boss? Yeah.
你沒事吧 老大 沒事
Just because we keep living doesn't mean we stop hurting.
永生不代表不會疼
Why us?
為什么是我們
Yeah.
是啊
That way madness lies.
再想下去會發瘋的
出自《李爾王》
I thought you were the brains of this outfit.
我還以為你是隊里的智囊呢
Tell you what I do wonder...
其實我好奇的是
is why you?
為什么是你
And why now?
為什么是現在
How old is Andy?
安迪多大了
Well, she says she... she doesn't remember.
她說 她不記得了
And she may not. I don't know.
也許真的不記得了 我也不清楚
But what I do know is she was alone for a long time
不過我知道 她找到同類之前
before she found anyone like her.
獨自一人度過了很長時間
A very long time.
非常漫長的時間
What about you? You have someone?
你呢 有人陪伴著你嗎
Just my family.
只有家人
I had three sons.
我有過三個兒子
And the youngest one, Jean Pierre...
年齡最小的 叫讓·皮埃爾
was the last one to die.
他是最后一個去世的
He was 42 when...
他那時42歲
cancer took him.
癌癥奪走了他的生命
The only way is forward now.
別無選擇 只能前進
What do you mean?
什么意思
You'll always and forever be the young woman right there...
你永生永世都會是現在這個年輕女人的模樣
but everyone around you,
可你身邊的每個人
everyone you love...
你愛的每個人
is gonna grow old,
都會變老
is gonna...
都會
is gonna suffer and is gonna die.
受盡痛苦 然后死去
And if you try to...
要是你試著
if you try to touch their lives...
要是你參與到他們的生活中去
well, they will get to learn your secret.
他們就會發現你的秘密
They will beg you to share it with them,
他們會求你分享你的能力
and you won't be able to.
但你沒辦法分享
And they won't believe you, of course.
當然 他們不會相信你
And they will tell you...
他們會說
that you don't love them.
你不愛他們
That your love is weak...
你的愛太脆弱
or selfish.
太自私
And you will never forget...
而你永遠都忘不了
the hate...
他們眼中的
and despair in their eyes.
恨意與絕望
And you will know what it is to lose...
到那時 你就真正懂得了
everyone you've ever loved.
失去一切心愛之人是什么樣的滋味
創可貼  優碘
Do you have a bathroom?
這里有洗手間嗎
No.
沒有
But we have a storeroom.
不過有間儲藏室
Do you need help?
你需要幫助嗎
Stitches would be better, but...
最好縫針 不過
this will help.
這也能將就一下
You haven't asked.
你還沒問我
Your business is yours.
那是你的事
You need help.
你需要幫助
What does it matter why?
原因重要嗎
Today, I put this on your wound.
今天 我幫你處理傷口
Tomorrow...
明天
you help someone up when they fall.
別人有難 你也會伸出援手
We're not meant to be alone.
我們并非生而孤獨
There.
好了
This should do.
應該可以了
Thank you.
謝謝你
Andromache, help me!
安德洛瑪刻 幫幫我
Why won't it stop?
血為什么流個不停
This can't be happening.
這不可能
Lykon.
蘭肯
It's time.
到時間了
It's impossible.
不可能
It...
到
It's time.
到時間了
How long will the testing take?
試驗要花多久
Until we have results we can replicate.
一直到我們獲得可復制的結果為止
Do you feel the wound trying to close?
你能感受到傷口愈合嗎
You don't need them for that.
不用他們也能獲得結果
You've got the samples, blood, tissue, DNA.
你已經拿到了樣本 血樣 組織 DNA
Well, you know the concept of proprietary data,
你懂得什么叫專有數據吧
and they're the product.
他們就是專有數據的產物
They go in the vault. They stay there under lock and key.
他們得被關在保險庫里 嚴加看管
For... ever?
永遠嗎
We can't have them strolling back out into the world...
我們可不能讓他們重回人世
into my competitors' laps.
落入競爭對手的手中
If this takes years, maybe decades,
就算花上幾年 幾十年
what does it matter to them?
對他們來說又有什么區別
If we can unlock their genetic code,
如果我們能破解他們的遺傳密碼
the world will be begging us for the key.
整個世界都會乞求我們手中的答案
Remarkable.
非同尋常
You will not be able to give him what he wants.
你給不了他想要的結果
You think I go too far?
你覺得我太過火了嗎
That I am unethical?
違背了倫理嗎
I would say immoral.
在我看來是不道德
I believe this can change the world.
我相信這能改變世界
A fine justification.
只是冠冕堂皇的理由
I've heard it so many times before.
我聽過無數遍了
As much as I like watching you sleep, I'm glad you're awake.
雖然我很愛看你睡覺 不過還好你醒了
Bed head?
頭發壓亂了
Nicely tousled.
凌亂得恰到好處
Do you know, I was thinking about Malta.
你知道嗎 我一直在想馬耳他
What time in Malta?
在馬耳他的哪一次
That time in Malta.
那一次啊
We should go back there.
我們應該回那里去
That would be nice.
那樣一定很好
Your mom and brother?
你媽媽和弟弟嗎
You have my phone?
你拿了我的手機
Where's your father?
你爸爸呢
Killed in action when I was 11.
他在我11歲時陣亡了
Here...
看
My mom, she was drowning after he died.
他死后 我媽痛不欲生
South Side of Chicago,
在芝加哥南部
a million different ways we could have went left.
我們一不小心就可能流連失所
She fought for us.
但她為我們拼盡全力
Never backed down.
從未退縮過
Never let us back down either.
也從不讓我們退縮
You come from warriors.
你出身軍旅之家
Yeah.
對
I do.
確實
I can't remember what my mother looked like.
我記不起我母親的長相了
Or my sisters.
也記不起我的姐妹
None of them.
都不記得了
Time steals it all away, I guess.
我猜是被時間偷走了
It's not what time steals...
重要的不是時間偷走了什么
it's what it leaves behind.
而是時間留下了什么
Things you can't forget.
有些事情你忘不掉的
I gave up searching for her.
我放棄了繼續搜尋她
I made Quynh a promise and I broke it.
我對瓊做出了承諾 卻沒有履行它
I'm getting Joe and Nicky back.
我要把喬和尼基救回來
Whatever it takes.
不惜一切代價
"Whatever it takes"?
"不惜一切代價"
Yes.
對
Guys, I found something.
伙計們 我有發現
An address just outside of London.
一個倫敦城外的地址
We gotta go.
我們得走了
■
薩里郡
英國
Go scout the back.
到后面偵查去
I can't do this.
我做不到
Yes, you can.
你能
I mean, I'm not doing this.
我是說 我不做
You're one of us now.
你現在是我們中的一員
We would do the same for you.
我們也會為你這么做
I never even had a choice. None of us had a choice.
我根本沒有選擇 我們都沒有選擇
There isn't a choice.
根本不存在選擇
The day I died,
我死那天
I killed the guy that killed me.
我殺了那個殺了我的人
They try to condition us, you know?
軍隊訓練我們的條件反射
Thousands of hours of training.
訓練了幾千小時
Two shots, quick kill.
兩槍就能利落地殺人
But they can't teach you how to live with it.
但是他們沒法教我們如何承受內疚
You've gotta feel it, Nile.
這是你的必經之路 奈爾
Every one.
人人都是如此
I saw what you did in that church.
我看到你在那間教堂里做的事了
All those bodies.
那些尸體
Is that supposed to be me?
你是要我那么做嗎
Is that what we're supposed to do, and we don't even know why?
我們應該那么做嗎 而我們甚至都不知道原因
You think knowing is gonna make you sleep better at night?
你覺得知道原因就能睡得安穩嗎
I can't be that.
我不能那么做
My family,
我的家人
they're gonna get old and I won't,
他們會變老 而我不會
but it'll be years before they realize that.
但他們要過好多年才會注意到
I still have time with them.
我仍然有時間和他們在一起
Here.
給
Take the car,
把車開走
and when you ditch it, ditch the weapons.
棄車時也把武器一起丟掉
You gonna be okay?
你沒問題嗎
Always.
永遠沒問題
Where's Nile?
奈爾去哪了
You and me, Book. Now and always.
只有你我 布克 從現在直到永遠
Guildford station in one mile.
距桂福德站不到兩公里
火車站  須安檢
Empty?
空的
Shit.
見鬼
Andy.
安迪
Where are they?
他們在哪
Andromache the Scythian.
斯基臺人安德洛瑪刻
The eternal warrior.
永生的戰士
Book? I'm right here.
布克 我在
Where are Joe and Nicky?
喬和尼基在哪
What are you doing?
你在做什么
Calm down.
冷靜
What are you doing? Andy, calm down!
你在做什么 安迪 冷靜
No!
不
You set us up?
你設計了我們
Please listen.
聽好
When my wife died,
我妻子死后
I devoted myself to your work.
我沉迷于研究你
I learned your secret history,
我挖掘出隱藏在歷史夾縫中
written in the margins...
如同傳說一樣流傳的
希臘
passed on like legend.
你的神秘經歷
安德洛瑪刻
悲劇
What was dismissed as a myth was, in fact, immortality.
你的永生被人們當作不實的神話
You could help end... needless suffering.
你可以幫助減少無謂的痛苦
Humanity needs you to share your gifts.
你們需要把天賦分享給人類
Humanity can screw itself.
管人類去死
Andy... Don't, you fucking coward.
安迪 滾開 你這懦夫
Why?
為什么
Why, Book?
為什么 布克
Andy, listen... Why?
安迪 聽我說 為什么
If Merrick can discover how we keep living,
如果梅里克能揭示我們永生的秘密
he might find a way how to end it.
也許他就能找到終結永生的方法
That's what you wanted.
這是你的心愿
Oh, Book. What have you done?
布克 你都做了什么
Not like this, Book.
不是這樣 布克
What's going on?
怎么回事
You're still bleeding.
你還在流血
What? Shit.
什么 見鬼
She's not healing.
她沒有愈合
What? Look at this. She's not healing.
什么 看這個 她還在流血
Go get something. Go on! Go on!
去拿東西止血 快點
Andy, look at me.
安迪 看著我
Look at me.
看著我
Why didn't you tell me?
你為什么不告訴我
It wouldn't have changed anything.
說了也不會改變什么
Hurry up!
快點
Come on.
過來
Careful.
小心點
Get her out of here.
帶她離開這里
Secure him.
抓住他
Nice work, Copley.
做得好 科普利
Look at you.
看看你
She's wounded. Gunshot.
她受傷了 槍傷
Why isn't she healing?
她為什么沒有愈合
I don't know.
我不知道
She's not immortal.
她并非永生不死
What do you mean, "Not immortal?" I mean it's gone.
什么意思 就是說能力消失了
You're a bloody mess.
你傷得好重
Now, how old are you?
你多大了
Come closer and I'll tell you.
靠近點 我來告訴你
Let's get them home.
把他們帶回去
Let her go. Cover me.
放她走 掩護我
No! No! Let her go!
不 不 放開她
Get her up.
把她弄起來
No!
不
I'm sorry, Andy.
對不起 安迪
I'm sorry.
對不起
Hold him still.
抓好他
Mr. Merrick, look. If it's
梅里克先生 聽著
true and she's somehow not immortal anymore,
如果她真的失去能力了
then she might not survive the testing.
她可能撐不過試驗
This will be murder.
那就是謀殺了
As if the CIA never disappeared anyone.
說得好像中情局沒殺過人一樣
As if they never conducted covert research.
好像他們沒有做過秘密研究一樣
No.
不
No, this is not what we agreed.
我們說好的不是這樣
We don't stop.
我們可不會停手
梅里克藥業
Andy.
安迪
What happened?
出了什么事
She's not healing.
她的傷口沒有愈合
I killed her.
我殺了她
I need to get a line in her and stop the bleeding.
我得給她縫合并止血
Keep her alive at all costs.
不惜一切代價保住她的命
Don't you see? Between Sudan and now, something's changed.
你不明白嗎 蘇丹那次之后 有什么改變了
Find out what. This will stabilize her,
找到那個變量 這個能讓她鎮靜下來
but I have to stitch her
但是我得給她縫合
and give her antibiotics. Good.
然后給她注射抗生素 好
All things die.
萬物終有一死
What was that?
什么
Everything has to die, Mr. Merrick.
有生就有死 梅里克先生
The only reason we haven't...
我們沒死的唯一理由就是
is that it's not our time yet.
我們的死期還沒到
If it's now Andromache's, nothing you can do will stop it.
如果現在是安迪的死期 你做什么都阻止不了
You'd be surprised by what my products can do.
我的產品的效力會讓你大吃一驚的
I will carve slices off you for years to get what I want.
只要能達成目的 我可以年復一年的折磨你們
Your time is coming.
你的死期就快到了
As is yours.
你的也是
I expect results!
我要結果
Andy.
安迪
Are you Copley?
你是科普利嗎
He sent you to finish me off. Who?
他派你來殺我 誰
Where's Andy and Booker?
安迪和布克在哪
Who are you?
你是誰
Son of a bitch!
媽的
You're another one.
你是另一個
Yeah. I'm new.
對 我是新人
Where are they? They're in a lab...
他們在哪 在一個實驗室里
being tested.
接受試驗
Tortured.
被折磨
Merrick...
梅里克
he only cares about her immortality,
他只在乎她的永生能力
not what she's done with it.
不在乎她用永生達成的成就
"What she's done with it"?
"用永生達成的成就"
黑 山
Montenegro, 1916.
1916年 黑山
移民之女
She saved a family of refugees whose daughter would discover
她救了一家難民 其中的女兒
the technique for the early detection of diabetes.
后來發現了早期診斷糖尿病的方法
This one...
這個
Her grandson would save
她的孫子
317 people from the Khmer Rouge in Cambodia.
救了317人 帶他們逃脫柬埔寨紅色高棉暴政
數百人自紅色高棉死囚營脫身
This guy...
這個人
This man prevented an accidental nuclear exchange in 1978
在1978年阻止了意外的核戰爭爆發
and likely saved civilization as a result.
很可能間接拯救了人類
The famous...
有名的
and the unknown names.
和無名的人們
She saves a life,
她拯救一條生命
two, three generations later, we reap the benefits.
兩三代人之后 我們從中獲益
1915年
被安迪所救
She's in it.
她參與其中
She can't see it.
卻看不清全貌
But you could.
但你可以
You could and you gave them up.
你看清了 但還是出賣了他們
I thought it could be the end of disease.
我以為這能終結疾病
I thought it could be the end of suffering.
我以為這能終結苦難
She couldn't talk...
臨終時
at the end...
她都說不出話來
my wife.
我的妻子
She couldn't breathe.
她喘不上氣
I couldn't do...
但我卻
anything.
無能為力
It was supposed to be a gift...
這本該是送給全世界的
to the world.
禮物
It wasn't your gift to give.
這不是你能送的禮物
Why would the immortality end?
為什么永生會終結
What?
什么
She wouldn't stop bleeding.
她血流不止
Is she alive?
她還活著嗎
I know where they are.
我知道他們在哪
There's no cameras here.
這里沒有監控
That's how he gets people in and out unseen.
方便神不知鬼不覺地讓人進出
How many shooters on site? At least 30.
有多少槍手 至少三十個
Their boss, Keane, is ex Special Forces.
他們的老大基恩 是前特種部隊成員
What kind of CEO rolls around with his own personal army?
什么樣的總裁會整天帶著個人軍隊到處轉悠
These days?
這年頭嗎
Most of them.
大多數都會
What are you doing? I'm gonna make this right.
你在干什么 我要挽救這一切
Your dying won't do that.
你的死不能挽救什么
But I'm supposed to let you walk in there by yourself?
那我就要看著你一個人走進去嗎
Out of the two of us,
我們兩個之中
I'm the one who will walk out of there again,
我才是那個能活著走出來的人
one way or another.
無論是怎么出來
You got me here.
你帶我來就足夠了
There's a private lab on the 15th floor.
十五樓有個秘密實驗室
It's empty.
里面是空的
This will get you access.
這個能讓你進去
You should get out of here before the noise starts.
在槍聲響起前 你該趕緊離開
Good luck, Ms. Freeman.
祝你好運 弗里曼女士
Floor's closed. How'd you get up here?
這樓層封鎖了 你是怎么上來的
Sorry, I was just looking...
抱歉 我只是在找
Hands! Let me see your hands.
你的手 舉起你的雙手
Zero, this is Alpha 2 2.
總部 我是A22
Sir.
先生
Zero. Send.
這里是總部 請講
We've had an intruder. Target is down.
有人闖入 目標已擊斃
See if you can get an ID off the body.
檢查能否確認尸體身份
Shit!
糟了
TAC teams, find Merrick now!
戰術小隊 立刻找到梅里克
You selfish piece of shit! Joe, leave it. Please!
你這個自私的廢物 喬 別說了 拜托
What do you know of the weight of all these years alone?
你知道獨自一個人熬過這么多年有多難嗎
You're a very pathetic man, Booker. Joe, Stop.
你真可悲 布克 喬 別說了
You and Nicky always had each other, right?
你和尼基一直擁有彼此 不是嗎
And all we had...
而我們有的
was our grief.
只是悲痛
Well, now you have even more.
那你現在可以有更多悲痛了
Who the hell are you? Where's the lab?
你是誰 實驗室在哪
Shit!
該死
There's another one!
我們漏了一個
She's going for the rest of them.
她要去找她的伙伴們
Doctor's lab, now!
在博士實驗室 快去
I'm locking you down in the penthouse until this is over.
這一切結束前 我要把你鎖在頂層
Nile.
奈爾
Behind you!
小心身后
Nile!
奈爾
There's four shooters at the door and more coming.
門口有四個槍手 還有更多在趕來
Andy.
安迪
Immortal or not,
不管你是不是永生不死
you made a promise.
你承諾過
Whatever it takes.
不惜一切代價
I've seen it, Andy.
我看到了 安迪
I know all the good you've done.
我知道你做過的那些善事
You came back.
你回來了
Yeah.
是啊
No, just leave me here.
不 讓我留在這
No man left behind.
不能丟下任何人
There's always a first time.
凡事總有第一次
He's nothing but a traitor. That's...
他不過是個叛徒
Stop! This is not the time for it.
閉嘴 現在不是互相指責的時候
We don't get a say in when it ends. We never have.
我們不能決定什么時候死 從來都不能
But we can control how we live.
但我們可以決定怎么活
And to be honest, Book,
而且說實話 布克
you and I,
你和我
we've been doing a shit job of it.
我們一直都活得不怎么樣
Now, get up.
給我起來
Let's go.
走吧
We stop Merrick here and now
我們必須在這里阻止梅里克
or he never stops coming after us.
不然他永遠都不會放過我們
Andy.
安迪
Are you sure?
你確定你可以嗎
This changes nothing.
這不會改變什么
We walk out of here like always.
我們會像以往那樣一起
Together.
活著出去
Let's get this motherfucker.
去抓那混蛋吧
Cover Andy.
掩護安迪
Andy!
安迪
Man! Andy!
天啊 安迪
Joe, Nicky, we're moving out!
喬 尼基 我們先出去
Assault team, move!
突擊隊 出發
You two, flank.
你們兩個 側方包圍
What's your location?
你們在哪
Enough of this shit.
我受夠了
Let's go. Andy.
走吧 去找安迪
Come on. Come on. Come on.
快 快 快
Shit! Jammed!
該死 卡住了
Where's Andy?
安迪去哪了
Hold at the bridge.
守住走廊
Roger that. Fuck.
收到 可惡
Where's Merrick?
梅里克在哪
Penthouse.
頂層
What do you think? Oslo 67?
你怎么想 67年奧斯陸那招
So Paulo 34. Nile's with me.
34年圣保羅 奈爾跟著我
What happened in So Paulo in 1934?
1934年圣保羅發生了什么
1834.
是1834年
You'll see.
你等著瞧吧
First team, hold the hall.
一隊 守住走廊
First team.
一隊
Wait for the signal.
等我信號
This gonna be like the last signal?
像上次那個信號一樣嗎
Go big or go home.
不成功便成仁
Keane.
基恩
Keane, how many more do we have coming?
基恩 我們還有多少增援
This is it.
沒有了
Dig in.
全體注意
I'll make the entry.
我來打頭
Stay tight to me, okay?
跟緊我 好嗎
I'll protect you.
我來保護你
I go through first.
我先上
I always go first.
一直都是我先
Andy, put on the damn armor.
安迪 穿上防彈衣
It's like Nicky said,
就像尼基說的
"If it's my time, it's my time."
"如果真的輪到了我 我躲不過的"
If this doesn't work out,
如果這次沒成功
next time, you go first.
下一次你先上
What the hell are they waiting for?
她們到底在拖什么
Shit!
該死
You shot Nicky.
你開槍打了尼基
You shouldn't have done that.
你不該那么做的
The elevator is going down!
電梯向下去了
Merrick is getting away! Go!
梅里克要逃走了 走
I'll stay with Andy.
我留下來陪安迪
You okay?
你還好嗎
Yeah, I'm fine.
還行
It just hurts.
就是有點疼
Actually, everything hurts.
事實上渾身都疼
Well, wait until tomorrow.
那明天有你好受的了
Can't wait.
我等不及了
I think you showed up when I lost my immortality.
我認為我失去永生能力的時候 你就出現了
So I could see what it was like.
這樣我就能看清楚
So I could remember.
我就可以想起來
Remember?
想起什么
Remember what it...
想起那種
what it was like to feel unbreakable.
堅不可摧的感覺
Remarkable.
無與倫比的感覺
You reminded me there are people...
是你提醒我世上還有許多
still worth fighting for.
值得為之奮戰的人
I know how I want to spend the time I've got left.
我明白自己想怎樣度過剩下的時間
You're gonna spend it with us, Andy.
你將和我們一起度過 安迪
You selfish little bitch!
你這個自私的賤人
I will kill her!
你敢動我就殺了她
All the lives you could save.
本來你可以拯救無數人
Don't you see what we could do here?
你難道不明白我們能成就什么嗎
You are priceless.
你是無價之寶
Hey, Nile.
奈爾
Do you think he speaks Russian?
你覺得他會說俄語嗎
Play dead, motherfucker.
給我裝死 混蛋
Nile?
奈爾
She's okay.
她沒事
Come on.
來吧
Faster than the elevator.
比電梯快多了
It's okay, Nile.
沒事了 奈爾
Give me your hand.
手伸過來
Let's go.
我們走吧
五百年來
本酒吧招待了各種各樣的顧客
錫制吧臺在十九世紀很普遍
本酒吧是少數幸存到二十世紀的
可說是現存英國歷史最悠久的酒吧
How's it going?
情況怎么樣
They're still deciding.
他們還在考慮
There's not much to decide.
沒什么好考慮的
It's not like they can kill me.
他們又不能把我給殺了
Oh, she gave it back?
她還給你了嗎
Yeah.
是啊
Talked to Copley.
跟科普利談過了
Said he could fix it.
他說他能搞定
Make it look like I was killed in action.
把我偽裝成是陣亡的
My family will mourn, but, uh...
我的家人會為我哀悼 但是
They'll be able to move on.
他們總會向前看的
It's just like what we did with my dad.
就像我們面對我爸去世時一樣
I just really want to hear my mom's voice one more time.
我只是想再聽一次我媽的聲音
You're a good kid, Nile.
你是個好孩子 奈爾
You're gonna be great for the team.
在隊伍里你會大有所為的
There's got to be a price.
你肯定得付出代價
One hundred years from today, they'll meet you here.
一百年后的今天 他們會在這里等你
Till then, you're alone.
在那之前 你要孤身一人
I hoped for less, but...
我希望處罰能輕些 但是
I expected more.
我本以為會更重
Nile was gonna let you off with an apology.
奈爾本來打算讓你道歉就行了
Just give her some time.
再多給她點時間
I'm gonna miss you.
我會想念你的
I won't see you again.
我再也見不到你了
Have a little faith, Book.
有點信心 布克
喬.尼基
1968年
尼基·史密斯
土耳其
喬  尼基
1956 1959
古巴革命
布克 尼基 喬
約瑟夫·瓊斯
This is only what I've found going back the last 150 years or so.
這些只是過去150多年里我能找到的
柏林  1989
自由的滋味
被安迪救下
When you think about how old you are,
每當你想到自己的年齡時
the good you've done for humanity becomes exponential.
你為人類做過的善事是它的指數倍
Maybe this is the why, Andy.
可能這就是我們存在的原因 安迪
It's nearly impossible
如今這個年代
to disappear in the world we live in today.
想要銷聲匿跡幾乎是不可能的
There are too many people like you who can bend it to your will.
有太多像你這樣的人想要利用我們
Too many with bad intentions.
有太多不良的企圖
We don't have all the answers, but we do have purpose.
我們不知道所有的答案 但我們有使命
And you're going to help us.
你要幫助我們
When we leave a footprint in the sand, in the snow, in the ether,
當我們在沙里 雪里 空中留下蹤跡
you're going to sweep it.
你要把它們抹除
You're going to protect us
你要保護我們
from those who want to put us in cages,
以防有人想把我們關進牢籠
and you're gonna help us find those jobs...
你要幫我們找到那些
that are best suited to us.
最適合我們的任務
She's not asking.
她不是在和你商量
I'd be honored.
這是我的榮幸
Then let's go to work.
那就開工吧
永 生 守 衛
六 個 月 后
■
巴黎
Booker.
布克
It's nice to finally meet you.
很高興終于見到你了